Guide to the David Plowden Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Plowden photographs and papers
1948-2011
WA MSS S-2957
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
64.0
(228 boxes)
This collection consists of photographs and papers that document the work of David Plowden as a photographer and author, 1948-2011. The photographic work in the collection records scenes from main streets and churches in small towns to barns and grain elevators in farmlands, as well as industrial cityscapes of cities like Chicago, Illinois, and New York City. The images also document railroads and their infrastructures, as well as bridges and canals throughout the United States and Canada, and maritime vessels, such as tugboats, steamboats, and ferries, which use the North American rivers, lakes, and harbors. A group of photographs also document sites related to Abraham Lincoln, which Plowden used in his work, Lincoln and His America (New York: Viking Press, 1970).
Plowden, David, 1932-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David Plowden on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, and the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1995-2012.
Gift of David Plowden, 2002 and 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
In 1995, when Yale received more than four thousand silver-gelatin prints from David Plowden, Mr. Plowden designated the works as "Exhibition," "Reproducible," and "Study" prints. Exhibition prints may be publically exhibited and, with appropriate permission, reproduced. Reproducible prints, with appropriate permission, may be reproduced. Study prints may only be examined but never reproduced. Reproducible and Study prints sometimes represent early prints of images that are also represented by Exhibition prints. In other cases, they may be the only print in the collection from a particular negative.
Mr. Plowden, his heirs and assigns retain all commercial rights in his photographs and writings. By agreement with Mr. Plowden, Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library has the limited right to authorize scholars to reproduce up to ten of Mr. Plowden’s images in a scholarly publication.
Box 177 (computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
David Plowden
David Plowden (born 1932, Yale 1955) is an American photographer noted for his exploration of the ways that agriculture and industry have reshaped the American landscape and built environments. Since 1952, when he began methodically photographing steam locomotives, Plowden has studied, documented, and commented on the transformation of urban and rural spaces through his individual photographs and more than twenty photographic books.
After graduating Yale College in 1955, Plowden worked briefly for the Great Northern Railway before beginning a career in photography. From 1957 to 1962, he studied under Minor White and Nathan Lyons, and served as an assistant to O. Winston Link and George Meluso. He received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1968 and a Smithsonian Institution Research Grant in 1970. Plowden has taught at the Institute of Design at the Illinois Institute of Technology, the School of Journalism at the University of Iowa, the University of Baltimore and Grand Valley State University in Michigan.
In 1995, Plowden and Yale University agreed that at the end of his career he would transfer his archive of notes, negatives, and prints to Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library. His work is also represented in the permanent collections of the Smithsonian Institution, the International Museum of Photography and Film at the George Eastman House, the Center for Creative Photography at the University of Arizona, the Art Institute of Chicago, the Albright Knox Art Gallery, and the Library of Congress.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photographs and papers that document the work of David Plowden as photographer and author from 1948 through 2011. His photographs record scenes from main streets and churches in small towns to the barns and grain elevators of American farmlands to the industrial landscapes of cities like Chicago and New York. Plowden's images depict steam railroads, their equipment, tracks, and operators; bridges, canals, and roadways throughout the United States and Canada; and such maritime vessels as tugboats, ferries, and commercial steamships which work the rivers, lakes, and harbors of North America. A group of photographs drawn from his book Lincoln and His America (New York: Viking Press, 1970) documents the contemporary appearance of sites related to Abraham Lincoln.
Photographs in the collection consist of nearly 5,400 black and white photographic prints, which include 2200 exhibition prints (silver gelatin and ink jet) and over 3,000 additional silver prints suitable for reproduction or study by researchers. The collection includes 45 color photographic prints and more than 2,700 color transparencies. The collection also includes a small number of digital image files created by Plowden from his photographic negatives and used by him to make some of the ink jet prints in the collection..
Papers in the collection include correspondence, research notes, and drafts related to his photographs and photographic books, as well as copies articles and clippings of works that reproduced his images.
The guide to the collection includes distinct entries for nearly every photographic print. The entries include Plowden's titles for the image, the place and date the image was made, and Mr. Plowden's image number, in parenthesis. Some images with the same or similar visual content may have variant titles and occasionally variant place designations. Some discrete images may share the same image number which usually indicates that they were made as part of a single project. Photographic prints in the collection are predominantly black-and-white silver gelatin prints. Exceptions such as color or ink jet prints are noted.
Mr. Plowden designated his prints as "Exhibition," "Reproducible," and "Study." Exhibition prints may be publically exhibited and, with appropriate permission, reproduced. Reproducible prints, with appropriate permission, may be reproduced. Study prints may only be examined but never reproduced. Reproducible and Study prints sometimes represent early prints of images that are also represented by Exhibition prints. In other cases, they may be the only print in the collection from a particular negative.
Mr. Plowden, his heirs and assigns retain all commercial rights in his photographs and writings. By agreement with Mr. Plowden, Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library has the limited right to authorize scholars to reproduce up to ten of Mr. Plowden's images in a scholarly publication.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Photographs, 1948-2011. II. Papers, circa 1957-2002.
Barns -- Pictorial works; Bridges -- Pictorial works; Canals -- Pictorial works; Church Buildings -- Pictorial works; City and town life -- Pictorial works; Farms -- Pictorial works; Ferries -- Pictorial works; Grain elevators -- Pictorial works; Harbors -- Pictorial works; Lakes -- Pictorial works; Railroads -- Pictorial works; Rivers -- Pictorial works; Steam locomotives -- Pictorial works; Steamboats -- Pictorial works; Tugboats -- Pictorial works; Canada -- Pictorial works; Chicago (Ill.) -- Pictorial works; New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; United States -- Pictorial works; Born digital; Photographic prints; Transparencies; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 ( Pictorial works); Plowden, David, 1932-
- Photographs, 1948-2011; Series I; 189; 41.9 linear_feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  Mr. Plowden designated his prints as "Exhibition," "Reproducible," and "Study." Exhibition prints may be publically exhibited and, with appropriate permission, reproduced. Reproducible prints, with appropriate permission, may be reproduced. Study prints may only be examined but never reproduced. Reproducible and Study prints sometimes represent early prints of images that are also represented by Exhibition prints. In other cases, they may be the only print in the collection from a particular negative. Mr. Plowden, his heirs and assigns retain all commercial rights in his photographs and writings. By agreement with Mr. Plowden, Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library has the limited right to authorize scholars to reproduce up to ten of Mr. Plowden's images in a scholarly publication.
  Arrangement
  Organized into sixteen subseries: July 1995 Acquisition, June 1999 Acquisition, July 2000 Acquisition, July 2001 Acquisition, July 2002 Acquisition, July 2003 Acquisition, July 2004 Acquisition, July 2005 Acquisition, July 2006 Acquisition, June 2008 Acquisition, January 2009 Acquisition, April 2009 Acquisition, April 2010 Acquisition, May 2011 Acquisition, July 2012 Acquisition, and July 2014 Acquisition.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of photographs, including silver gelatin prints, inkjets, and digital files, created and printed by Plowden from 1948-2011, and incrementally acquired by the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1995-2014.
  For ease of intellectual access, titles of photographs appear aphabetically within each box in this series. As boxes are consulted for research and study the actual order of the photographs within a box will frequently change.
  - July 1995 Acquisition
    Custodial History
    Purchased from David Plowden on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1995.
    Organized under three headings: Exhibition Prints, Reproducible Prints and Study Prints, and Color Transparencies.
    Photographic prints of images created by Plowden and printed by him, as well as color transparencies. The titles listed in the finding aid were created by Mr. Plowden. They are accompanied, wherever possible, by Plowden's image number, listed in parenthesis. The dates listed in the finding aid represent when Mr. Plowden exposed the image. The date on which Mr. Plowden made the particular print is often, but not always, noted on the individual prints.
    - Exhibition Prints
      - Approaching the 98th Meridian. Steele County, North Dakota (GFB-68-2588), 1968 (Box 1)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway 4-6-2 type locomotive #2408 in round house, The Glen Engine Terminal. Montreal, Quebec, Canada (CPR-360-2408), 1960 March (Box 1)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway Engineer "Oiling Round", 4-6-2 Type Steam Locomotive, The Glen Engine Terminal. Montreal, Quebec, Canada (CPR-360), 1960 March (Box 1)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway Freight Yard. Megantic, Quebec, Canada (CPR-360-1-H), 1960 March (Box 1)
      - Charging Open Hearth Furnace, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1630), 1979 (Box 1)
      - Coxsackie, New York (1073-118), 1973 October (Box 1)
      - Detail of Rolling Stand, 80 Inch Hot Strip Mill, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2004), 1979 (Box 1)
      - Erie-Lackawanna Railroad, Westbound "Phoebe Snow." Scranton, Pennsylvania (PA-164-292), 1964 January (Box 1)
      - Faxon, Oklahoma (969-686), 1969 September (Box 1)
      - Firehold, Steamer William A. McGonagle, Kinsman Lines. Buffalo, New York (685-1478), 1985 June (Box 1)
      - Lakeside Press. Chicago, Illinois (C-1183-146), 1983 November (Box 1)
      - Reading Company 4-8-4 Type Locomotive, # 2101 Driving Wheel Detail. Shamokin, Pennsylvania (RDG/IHR-32), 1963 (Box 1)
      - The Starrucca Viaduct. Lanesboro, Pennsylvania (273-188), 1973 February (Box 1)
      - Steamer Kinsman Independent. Superior, Wisconsin (685-994), 1985 June (Box 1)
      - Ann Arbor Railroad Depot. Mount Pleasant, Michigan (975-2450), 1975 September (Box 2)
      - Corn Cribs by Highway. Marshall County, Illinois (681-315), 1981 June (Box 2)
      - Entrance, Van's Clothing. Victor, Iowa (686-879), 1986 June (Box 2)
      - Farm. Will County, Illinois (481-2), 1981 April (Box 2)
      - Grain Elevator. Antelope, Montana (GP-630), 1971 (Box 2)
      - Grain Elevators. Golden Valley, North Dakota (GP-253), 1971 (Box 2)
      - Harvested Wheat Fields. Near Dusty, Washington (CP-1194), 1973 (Box 2)
        Although filed within exhibition prints, Plowden later designated this print as a reproducible (plus) print.
      - Hillsboro, New Hampshire (475-857), 1975 April (Box 2)
      - Independent Order of Odd Fellows (I.O.O.F.) Lodge Hall. Shullsburg, Wisconsin (1092-560), 1992 October (Box 2)
      - Jones County, Iowa (587-141), 1987 May (Box 2)
      - Main Street. Cazenovia, New York (NYS-366-35), 1966 March (Box 2)
      - Marion, Kansas (CP-632), 1973 (Box 2)
      - Methodist Church. Saline County, Missouri (874-542), 1974 August (Box 2)
      - Office, Erie Railroad Depot (Line Since Abandoned). Thompson, Pennsylvania (366-33), 1966 March (Box 2)
      - The Western House. Springville, New York (892-743), 1992 August (Box 2)
      - Wheat Fields. Near Great Falls, Montana (GP-322), 1971 (Box 2)
      - Chair, Johnson House. Peterson, Iowa (686-405), 1986 June (Box 3)
      - Chicago and Northwestern Railway Tracks. Near Mechanicsville, Iowa (486-178), 1986 April (Box 3)
      - Clarence Cooperative. Clarence, Iowa (987-143), 1987 September (Box 3)
      - Crosshead Detail Pennsylvania Railroad 0-6-0 type locomotive, #5244 last active Pennsylvania Railway steam locomotive, Union Transport Company. New Egypt, New Jersey (UTC-1961-Roll 10 #10) (Box 3)
      - Dining Room, Joe and Ellen Tetzloff's Home. Janesville, Minnesota (1091-1293), 1991 October (Box 3)
      - Fences. Near Rimouski, Quebec, Canada (GFB-69-1784), 1969 (Box 3)
      - Gramco Feed Mill. Springville, New York (892-541), 1992 August (Box 3)
      - Harvested Wheat Fields. Whitman County, Washington (CP-551), 1973 (Box 3)
      - Hotel Lobby. Columbus Junction, Iowa (1084-125), 1984 October (Box 3)
      - Post Office. Ogallah, Kansas (CP-1944), 1973 (Box 3)
      - Sea Cliff, New York (174-339), 1974 January (Box 3)
      - Soo Line Depot. Martin, North Dakota (GFB-68-2100), 1968 (Box 3)
      - St. Augustine's Church (1844). New Diggings, Wisconsin (1092-339), 1992 October (Box 3)
      - Statue of Liberty from Caven Point Road. Jersey City, New Jersey (467-1018), 1967 April (Box 3)
      - Village Hardware. Scales Mound, Illinois (1092-140), 1992 October (Box 3)
      - Barn. Near Angola, Indiana (969-905), 1969 September (Box 4)
      - Blast Furnace Cast House During Casting, Former Jones Laughlin (LTV Corp.), Indiana Harbor Works. East Chicago, Indiana (JL-682-76), 1982 June (Box 4)
      - Carter, Montana (GP-1655), 1971 (Box 4)
      - Former Jones Laughlin Steel (LTV Corp.), Indiana Harbor Works. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2503), 1979 (Box 4)
      - General Mills South Chicago Grain Elevator. Chicago, Illinois (C-183-983), 1983 January (Box 4)
      - Funnel Detail, Steamer Henry Steinbrenner (formerly the William A. McGonagle). Buffalo, New York (789-572), 1989 July (Box 4)
      - Grain Elevator. Duluth, Minnesota (GFB-68-4183), 1968 (Box 4)
      - Grain Elevators, Buffalo River. Buffalo, New York (1085-1972), 1985 October (Box 4)
      - New York Central Railroad Steam Tug, New York Central No. 31. Weehawken, New Jersey (NYH-ST-NYC-263-62), 1963 February (Box 4)
      - Pittsburgh Coke Company (U.S. Steel), Clairton Works. Clairton, Pennsylvania (PB-1162-103), 1962 November (Box 4)
      - "Puddler" in Blast Furnace Cast House, LTV Steel, Indiana Harbor Works. East Chicago, Indiana (JL-482-154), 1982 April (Box 4)
      - Slagging Ingots, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1574), 1979 (Box 4)
      - Steamer Crispin Oglebay (Stern View), Columbia Steamships. Milwaukee, Wisconsin (1190-242A), 1990 November (Box 4)
      - Steamer Kinsman Independent II. Duluth, Minnesota (685-545), 1985 June (Box 4)
      - Steamer S. T. Crapo, Inland Lakes Management, on Lake Michigan, Cabin Door Detail. Lake Michigan (790-200), 1990 July (Box 4)
      - Steel Works. Indiana Harbor, Indiana (IS-2573), 1979 (Box 4)
      - [Doremus Avenue]. Newark, New Jersey (NJ-164-55), 1964 January (Box 5)
      - Gallitzin, Pennsylvania (875-232), 1975 August (Box 5)
      - Girl in Window. Cresson, Pennsylvania (875-364), 1975 August (Box 5)
      - Gotebo, Oklahoma (969-337), 1969 September (Box 5)
      - Great Northern Railway Freight Train West. Havre, Montana (GFB-68-1344), 1968 (Box 5)
      - Harlan County, Kentucky (374-801), 1974 March (Box 5)
      - Indian Reservation. Cache Creek, British Columbia, Canada (GFB-68-4569), 1968 (Box 5)
      - Man on bicycle. Chicago, Illinois (C-982-399), 1982 September (Box 5)
      - Mayetta, Kansas (591-820), 1991 June (Box 5)
        Although filed within exhibition prints, Plowden later designated this print as a reproducible print.
      - Sandusky, Ohio (969-915), 1969 September (Box 5)
      - Shopping Center. Wausau, Wisconsin (880-32), 1980 August (Box 5)
      - Shopping Mall. Beaver Dam, Wisconsin (481-470), 1981 April (Box 5)
      - Tract House. Warrenville, Illinois (881-300), 1981 August (Box 5)
      - Chesapeake City, Maryland (171-26), 1971 January (Box 6)
      - Chicago, Illinois (181-58), 1981 January (Box 6)
      - Keystone, West Virginia (374-1070), 1974 March (Box 6)
      - The Mid-Hudson Bridge. Poughkeepsie, New York (GFB-69-109), 1969 (Box 6)
      - Point Marion, Pennsylvania (374-69), 1974 March (Box 6)
      - Putnam, Connecticut (475-705), 1975 April (Box 6)
      - Secaucus, New Jersey (174-512), 1974 January (Box 6)
      - Street by Abandoned Textile Mills. New Bedford, Massachusetts (475-616), 1975 April (Box 6)
      - The Tunkhannock Viaduct. Nicholson, Pennsylvania (273-196), 1973 February (Box 6)
      - The Tyrone Bridge, Kentucky River. Tyrone, Kentucky (GFB-68-980), 1968 (Box 6)
      - U.S. Steel, Gary Works, from Indiana Dunes State Park. Gary, Indiana (GL-473-174), 1973 April (Box 6)
      - World Trade Center from Johnson Avenue. Jersey City, New Jersey (1072-90), 1972 October (Box 6)
      - Yaquina Bay Bridge. Newport, Oregon (GFB-68-2816), 1968 (Box 6)
      - Yaquina Bay Bridge. Newport, Oregon (GFB-68-5576), 1968 (Box 6)
      - Amoco Oil Refinery. Whiting, Indiana (1081-81), 1981 October (Box 7)
      - Bosler, Wyoming (874-617), 1974 August (Box 7)
      - Cooling Tower, Nuclear Generating Station. Stillman Valley, Illinois (681-140), 1981 June (Box 7)
      - East of Las Vegas, New Mexico (471-179), 1971 April (Box 7)
      - Gas Station by I-57 Interchange. Peotone, Illinois (281-91), 1981 February (Box 7)
      - Intersection. Near Waukon, Allamakee County, Iowa (387-131), 1987 March (Box 7)
      - Near Faith, South Dakota (GP-1170), 1971 (Box 7)
      - Near Pullman, Washington (CP-454), 1973 (Box 7)
      - Piles of Taconite Pellets, Burlington Northern Railway Yard. Superior, Wisconsin (679-340), 1979 June (Box 7)
      - Steamer Crispin Oglebay, Columbia Steamships, View of Engine from Crank Deck of Engine Room. Probably in Milwaukee, Wisconsin (1190-608), 1990 November (Box 7)
      - Tract House. Near Manteno, Illinois (281-185), 1981 (Box 7)
      - U.S. Route 93. North of Wells, Nevada (CP-1782), 1973 (Box 7)
      - Bloomfield Bridge. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (PB-567-539), 1967 May (Box 8)
      - Chicago, Illinois (1078-192), 1978 October (Box 8)
      - Chicago, Illinois (1079-235), 1979 October (Box 8)
      - Clinton, New Jersey (GFB-469-361), 1969 April (Box 8)
      - Coal Tipple on Norfolk Western Railway Mine Spur. Slab Fork, West Virginia (374-1590), 1974 March (Box 8)
      - Denville, Kentucky (374-431), 1974 March (Box 8)
      - Empire Mine. Palmer, Michigan (679-597), 1979 June (Box 8)
      - National Steel Taconite Mine. Minnesota (679-345), 1979 June (Box 8)
      - ORTRAN Coal Loading Facility. Superior, Wisconsin (685-1950), 1985 June (Box 8)
      - Paul Bunyan, Frontier Village. Saint Ignace, Michigan (680-67), 1980 June (Box 8)
      - Power Shovel, Limestone Quarry. Upper Peninsula, Michigan (ISM-42), 1979 (Box 8)
      - Taconite Mine. Minnesota (ISM-15), 1979 (Box 8)
      - View looking south from UN Building. New York, New York (NYC-1166-18), 1966 November (Box 8)
      - Welch, West Virginia (374-920), 1974 March (Box 8)
      - Balling Mill, Taconite Plant, Empire Mine. Palmer, Michigan (679-720), 1979 June (Box 9)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway Number 2412. Montreal, Quebec, Canada (CPR-360-2412), 1960 March (Box 9)
      - Charging Open Furnace, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1679), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Limestone Quarry. Gulliver, Michigan (ISM-190), 1980 (Box 9)
      - Open Hearth Furnace, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1555), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Power Shovels, Midland Coal Co., Mecca Mine (abandoned). Toluca, Illinois (681-248), 1981 June (Box 9)
      - Puddler in Blast Furnace Cast House, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2345), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Rod Mill, Taconite Plant, Empire Mine. Palmer, Michigan (679-90), 1979 June (Box 9)
      - Slagging Ingots, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-328), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Taconite Plant ("MINTAC" U.S. Steel). Evelyn, Minnesota (685-1491), 1985 June (Box 9)
      - Teeming Ingots, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-804), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Ventilation Fan (Blower), Coal Mine. Sesser, Illinois (ISC-55), 1980 (Box 9)
      - View Looking Toward Blast Furnaces, Bethlehem Steel, Johnstown Works (Since Razed). Johnstown, Pennsylvania (875-450), 1975 August (Box 9)
      - Walker, Puddler in Blast Furnace Cast House, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2171), 1979 (Box 9)
      - Workhouse at Coal Mine. Sesser, Illinois (ISC-173), 1980 (Box 9)
      - 44 Inch Cold Strip Mill, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-515), 1979 (Box 10)
      - 80 Inch Hot Strip Mill (rolling mill), Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2015), 1979 (Box 10)
      - 80 Inch Hot Strip Mill, Inland Steel. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2283), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Basic Oxygen Furnace, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-747), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Blast Furnace "Down Comer". Indiana Harbor, Indiana (IS-1257), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway Hostler, Washing Steam Locomotive. McAdam, New Brunswick, Canada (CPR-759), 1959 July (Box 10)
      - Charging Open Hearth Furnace, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1630), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Denver and Rio Grande Western Railroad Locomotive Taking Sand. Chama, New Mexico (SE-RE-95), 1962 (Box 10)
      - Finishing Stands, Eighty Inch Hot Strip Mill, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2114), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Great Northern Railway, Extra 3387. Near Delano, Minnesota (GN-1956-12), 1956 February (Box 10)
      - LTV Steel, Rolling Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (C-483-390), 1983 April (Box 10)
      - Man Spraying Gunite into Basic Oxygen Furnace to patch refractory material within. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1462), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Rolling Stand, 84" Hot Strip Mill, Former Jones Laughlin (LTV Corp.), Indiana Harbor Works. East Chicago, Indiana (JL-482-506), 1982 April (Box 10)
      - Steel Mill, Coke Ovens (push side). East Chicago, Indiana (IS-1746), 1979 (Box 10)
      - Blast Furnace Row, Steel Mill. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-424), 1979 (Box 11)
      - Coal Piles near Coke Ovens. East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2394), 1979 (Box 11)
      - Former Jones Laughlin (LTV Corp.), Indiana Harbor Works. East Chicago, Indiana (JL-882-147), 1982 August (Box 11)
      - Former Jones Laughlin (LTV Corp.), Steel Mill. Indiana Harbor, East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2531), 1979 (Box 11)
      - Former Republic Steel Works. Chicago, Illinois (282-106), 1982 February (Box 11)
      - High Line, Steel Mill. Indiana Harbor, East Chicago, Indiana (No number extant), 1979 (Box 11)
      - Steamer Marlhill Unloading Ore. Indiana Harbor Canal, East Chicago, Indiana (IS-2), 1979 (Box 11)